[
  {
    "question": "World War II started when Germany invaded which country?",
    "answers": [
      "Belgium",
      "Great Britain",
      "France",
      "Poland"
    ],
    "correct": "Poland",
    "source": "https://www.britannica.com/quiz/world-war-ii-quiz"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of these best describes blitzkrieg, which was key to Germany's early success in the war?",
    "answers": [
      "Quick coordinated attacks",
      "Propaganda",
      "Economic sanctions",
      "High-level espionage"
    ],
    "correct": "Quick coordinated attacks"
  },
  {
    "question": "Early in the war, in his first address to the British House of Commons, Prime Minister Winston Churchill said, \"I have nothing to offer but...\"",
    "answers": [
      "\"Blood, toil, tears and sweat\"",
      "\"A swift end to tyranny\"",
      "\"Peace in our time\"",
      "\"An appeal to human decency\""
    ],
    "correct": "\"Blood, toil, tears and sweat\"",
    "no-open": true
  },
  {
    "question": "After World War I, France built the Maginot Line, a string of border fortifications considered impenetrable. How did the German army overcome the Maginot Line in World War II?",
    "answers": [
      "Bribed its way past it",
      "Overwhelmed it with troops",
      "Went around it",
      "Bombed it"
    ],
    "correct": "Went around it"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which technology helped the U.K. defeat Germany's months long air offensive against it in the Battle of Britain?",
    "answers": [
      "Radar",
      "Stealth airplanes",
      "Rockets",
      "Atomic energy"
    ],
    "correct": "Radar"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which fortuitous circumstance helped reduce U.S. losses at Pearl Harbor?",
    "answers": [
      "No American aircraft carriers were in port",
      "Strong winds blew Japanese planes off course",
      "Heavy fog made targeting ships difficult",
      "Base personnel awoke earlier than usual"
    ],
    "correct": "No American aircraft carriers were in port"
  },
  {
    "question": "Because Japan conquered the Dutch East Indies, which of these goods was first to be rationed in the United States?",
    "answers": [
      "Pineapples",
      "Tires",
      "Typewriters",
      "Sugar"
    ],
    "correct": "Tires"
  },
  {
    "question": "Japan launched an attack on the U.S. mainland by using which curious method?",
    "answers": [
      "Trained dolphins",
      "Helium balloons",
      "Amphibious tanks",
      "Scuba divers"
    ],
    "correct": "Helium balloons"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of these was key to U.S. success at the Battle of Midway?",
    "answers": [
      "Having cracked the main Japanese naval communications code",
      "Having better-trained pilots than the Japanese",
      "Having better aircraft",
      "Having a larger fleet"
    ],
    "correct": "Having cracked the main Japanese naval communications code",
    "no-open": true
  },
  {
    "question": "Based on the year they were first produced, which name was given to one of Japan's most highly effective fighter planes?",
    "answers": [
      "Zeroes",
      "Deuces",
      "Niners",
      "Thirty-eights"
    ],
    "correct": "Zeroes"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which city was the site of a 900-day siege during World War II?",
    "answers": [
      "Berlin",
      "Leningrad",
      "Stalingrad",
      "London"
    ],
    "correct": "Leningrad"
  },
  {
    "question": "Referring to a desperate maneuver used to sink Allied ships, kamikaze literally means what?",
    "answers": [
      "Floating mine",
      "Divine wind",
      "Iceberg",
      "Hungry shark"
    ],
    "correct": "Divine wind",
    "no-open": true
  },
  {
    "question": "Which language was used by the U.S. military to encode messages that were never deciphered by the enemy during World War II?",
    "answers": [
      "Welsh",
      "Greek",
      "Yiddish",
      "Navajo"
    ],
    "correct": "Navajo",
    "no-open": true
  },
  {
    "question": "The German military operation code-named Walk\u00c3\u00bcre (\"Valkyrie\") hoped to assassinate which leader?",
    "answers": [
      "Benito Mussolini",
      "Winston Churchill",
      "Adolf Hitler",
      "Franklin Roosevelt"
    ],
    "correct": "Adolf Hitler",
    "no-open": true
  },
  {
    "question": "The Tuskegee Airmen constituted a U.S. Army unit drawn from which group?",
    "answers": [
      "Women",
      "World War I veterans",
      "Youths under age 18",
      "African Americans"
    ],
    "correct": "African Americans"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which U.S. president won the Navy and Marine Corps Medal for his heroism during World War II?",
    "answers": [
      "Ronald Reagan",
      "Jimmy Carter",
      "John F Kennedy",
      "Dwight D Eisenhower"
    ],
    "correct": "John F Kennedy"
  },
  {
    "question": "Operation Bodyguard provided critical support to the Allies' D-Day invasion in which way?",
    "answers": [
      "Using deception to distract German forces",
      "Raising money by selling war bonds",
      "Assassinating key German generals",
      "Teaching American soldiers French phrases"
    ],
    "correct": "Using deception to distract German forces"
  },
  {
    "question": "A precursor to Nazi extermination camps, the \"Holocaust by bullets\" happened during which of these events?",
    "answers": [
      "Germany's occupation of France",
      "Germany's participation in the Spanish Civil War",
      "Germany's conclusion of an alliance with Italy",
      "Germany's invasion of the USSR"
    ],
    "correct": "Germany's invasion of the USSR",
    "no-open": true
  },
  {
    "question": "American General Anthony C. McAuliffe famously responded \"NUTS!\" when asked to surrender during which battle?",
    "answers": [
      "Battle of the Bulge",
      "Operation Barbarossa",
      "Siege of Warsaw",
      "Battle of Tannenberg"
    ],
    "correct": "Battle of the Bulge"
  },
  {
    "question": "\"Little Boy\" and \"Fat Man\" were nicknames for what?",
    "answers": [
      "Two invasion forces on D-Day",
      "Stalin and Churchill",
      "Italy and Germany",
      "Atomic bombs"
    ],
    "correct": "Atomic bombs"
  },
  {
    "question": "Still the home of a U.S. military base, which place was the site of the last major battle of World War II?",
    "answers": [
      "Guadalcanal",
      "Stalingrad",
      "Berlin",
      "Okinawa"
    ],
    "correct": "Okinawa"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which country suffered the most military deaths, by far, during World War II?",
    "answers": [
      "Germany",
      "Soviet Union",
      "France",
      "United States"
    ],
    "correct": "Soviet Union"
  },
  {
    "question": "Anticipating security needs after the war, the United States' Operation Paperclip sought to do what?",
    "answers": [
      "Prevent the spread of communism",
      "Rebuild Germany",
      "Recruit Nazi scientists",
      "Distribute aid to Jewish refugees"
    ],
    "correct": "Recruit Nazi scientists"
  }
]